Krishna Panthi

MS Student at Clemson, South Carolina ~ will be relocating to the job site

Email - kpanthi@clemson.edu, krishnapd133@gmail.com LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/krishnapanthi/ GitHub - https://github.com/kp-square

Summary

- Software developer and MS student with 3 years of professional experience.
- Led development of a sales system for a global company using .NET, Javascript, SQL, etc.
- Worked to migrate an existing WCF desktop application to a web application in Angular and .NET Core.

Skills

Programming Languages: C#, Python, JavaScript, SQL, C++, C

Frameworks: .NET core, Vue.js, Vuetify, Angular

Databases: MS-SQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Cloud: AWS, Microsoft Azure

Misc: Git, Visual Studio, Pycharm, IIS, Linux, LaTeX, GPT Api

ML Tools: Tensorflow, PyTorch, Pandas, Darts

Professional Experience

Clemson University - South Carolina, US Research Assistant and MS student Jan 2024 - Present

- Working under Assistant Prof. Vidya Samadi in Hydrosystem and Hydroinformatics Research Group.
- Worked in Time Series Analysis. This involved collecting relevant data, pre-processing it, building ML models or using existing ML models to train and test the future forecasts.
 Tools used include: Pandas, Pytorch, Tensorflow and Darts. Experimented with different types of models like MLP, LSTM and Transformer based models.
- Helped conduct a <u>hackathon</u> event. Mentored interns and juniors.

Mutualart - Israel Software Developer (Remote) November 2021 - Dec 2023

Worked as a software developer with a multitude of technologies.

- Led the development of the private sales system used for private sales of artworks sourced from private clients. Designed a database to manage the application data within SQL Server. Built a web application to interact with data which involved users, emails, artworks, communication workflows, etc using Vue 2 and .NET Core. Built background jobs to automate the tasks and workflows using Quartz.Net. Implemented algorithms for filtering out artworks and matching best fit clients to auction houses. Other technologies involved Elasticsearch, Mixpanel, AWS, GraphQL, IIS.
- Upgraded an existing ML tool implemented in Python 2 using opency to Python 3. Involved upgrading libraries, updating functions and syntax changes, bug fixing, etc.
- Worked on a Proof of Concept(POC) of Named Entity Recognition system for auto moderation of web scraped data in Python using Spacy. Generated data for the model using GPT-4 Api.

PensionPro - Harrisburg, PA

Junior Software Developer (via Dolphin Dive Technology, Kathmandu)

April 2021 - January 2022

Worked to migrate an existing WPF(Desktop) Application to a Web Application.

- In my first role as a software developer, I acquired key professional principles and honed
 my skills in using tools like change trackers and version controls. I also gained exposure
 to Scrum, fostering my abilities in collaborative work and agile project management.
- Implemented features for a web application using Angular 8 and .NET Core. This
 involved analyzing existing WPF application code to understand features and
 re-implementing them in Web. Part of the work involved optimizing existing SQL code.
 Other technologies involved Microsoft Azure, SQL server and Redis.

Education

MS in Computer Science - Clemson University, SC 2024 - Present

BE in Computer Engineering - Tribhuvan University, Nepal 2016 - 2021